Marty Mann Papers
Marty Mann Papers
- Recordings
  - National Council on Alcoholism Public Service Announcements, New York, NY, mann_m_173; radio public service announcements commissioned by the National Council on Alcoholism; 7" phonodisc
    1 - Silent Treatment / 2 - Silent Treatment / 3 - Progress / 4 - Progress
    [Side B is identical]"
  - National Council on Alcoholism Public Service Announcements, New York, NY, mann_m_175; public service announcements commissioned by the National Council on Alcoholism; 7" phonodisc
    1. Who Cares About Alcoholism? (:30) / 2. Your Wife is An Alcoholic! (:30) "
  - National Council on Alcoholism Public Service Announcement, New York, NY, mann_m_176; radio public service announcements commissioned by the National Council on Alcoholism; 1/4" reel tape (Box 15)
    "Cut 1 - 30 sec. The Typical Alcoholic NIMH-30-12 / Cut 2 - 60 sec. Some of Your Best Friends Are NIMH 60-13 / Cut 3 - 30 sec. Some of Your Best Friends Are NIMH-30-14 / Cut 4 - 60 sec. Cocktail Conversation NIMH-60-15 "
  - National Council on Alcoholism Public Service Announcements, St. Ansonia, Connecticut, 1974; mann_m_174; public service announcements commissioned by the National Council on Alcoholism; one side in English and one in Spanish; 7" phonodisc
    "1. Don't Let the Bottle Getcha (:60) / 2. Don't Let the Bottle Getcha (:30) / 3. Don't Let the Bottle Getcha (:20) / 4. Serenity Prayer (:60) / 5. Serenity Prayer (:60) / 6. Serenity Prayer (:20) "
  - National Institute of Mental Health Speakers, Mt. Airy Psychiatric Center, 02/16/1974; mann_m_082; 1/4" reel tape (Box 15)
    [Note on Box] / Participants: / Dr. Morris Chafetz / Mrs. Marty Mann / Event: Mt. Airy Pysch. Ctr. / Location: Denver, CO / Date: 02/16/74"
  - N.Y.C Medical Society of Alcoholism "Industrial Aspects of Alcoholism." Committee on Alcoholism in Industry, New York, NY, 02/09/1960; mann_m_002; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
  - Open End, WNEW-TV, New York, NY, 02/17/1963; mann_m_054; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box] "Alcoholism, Pleasure or Problem"
    [From inside of box] Open end - TV Show / Mrs Mann, Dr. Block / Dr. Muller, Dr. Beavan / Dr. McCall, Dr. Fox. / This is a two hour program of discussion. A lot of information about alcoholism is given but it is quite disorganized. nevertheless this is the most professional of discussion tapes and is a typical example of the Suskind technique. "
  - Practical Aspects of Medical Management and Rehabilitation of Alcoholics [conference], University of Utah Medical Center, June 19-21, 1968, Salt Lake City, Utah
    - [1 of 5], 06/19/1968; mann_m_059; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    - [2of 5], 06/19/1968; mann_m_060; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    - [3of 5], 06/20/1968; mann_m_061; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    - [4of 5], 06/20/1968; mann_m_062; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    - [5of 5], 06/21/1968; mann_m_063; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
  - R. Brinkley Smithers, "Viewpoint" for Episcopal Church, New York, NY, 08/27/1960; mann_m_049; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box] R. Brinkley Smithers / "Viewpoint" for Episcopal Church / Interview by Rev. Dana Kennedy / WOR & Mutual Network / Date: August 27, 1960 / Speed: 7.5
    [From note inside box] R. Brinkley Smithers / Question and answer session aimed at popular information level. Basic patterns and behavior of drinking alcoholically [sic]. Good state education programs mentioned. Importance of clergy counseling. Satisfaction from helping others. Mr. Smithers' delivery is faulty.
    [From back of box] VIEWPOINT / Broadcast over National Broadcasting Network 8/26/61 6:15-6:30 PM / Broadcast over station WOR (NYC) 8/27/61 7:05-7:20 AM / R. Brinkley Smithers"
  - Teen-age Drinking Forum (Parents League of New York City), New York, NY, mann_m_004; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
    Tape of panel discussion on teenage drinking held by the Parents League of New York City. Chairman- Yvelin Gardner; Panelists Win Edc (role of schools), John Parlchee (role of parents), Judge Elleson ("Darien Judge")
  - 2nd Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism, Honolulu, Hawaii, March 31 and April 1, 1960; sponsored by Hawaii Committee on Alcoholism
    - [Reel I] The Challenge of Alcoholism; Medicine & Alcoholism; Out of Orbit, March 31 and April 1, 1960; mann_m_034; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Recording of 2nd Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism in Honolulu, Hawaii on March 31 and April 1, 1960 / [Note on Box] / Second Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism / Sponsored by Hawaii Committee on Alcoholism / Thursday - March 31 / Registration: Lobby of Hotel 9:30-11:30 / 12:00 noon Luncheon / Introduction - Mr. Ted R. Scott / Invocation - The Reverend Lawrence S. Jones / Address - "Medicine & Alcoholism" - Aloysius S. Church, MD / Film: "Out of Orbit"
      Friday- April 1 / 6:00-7:00 p.m. - No Host Social Hour / 7:00 - 8:00 p.m. - Dinner - The Meeting House / Master of Ceremonies - Mr. Bob Roberts / Invocation - The Reverend John J Morrett / 15 Minute Question and Answer Period / Audience Participation / Moderator - Mr. Bob Roberts / Panel / Mr. Patrick Butler / Aloysius S. Church, MD / Mrs. Marty Mann / Mr. John C. Martelon / 8:15 p.m. - "The Challenge of Alcoholism" - Mrs. Marty Mann / Adjourment of Conference: Mrs. Peter K. McLean
    - [Reel II] Health, Education & Social Services; The Clergyman, 03/31/1960; mann_m_035; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Recording of 2nd Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism in Honolulu, Hawaii on March 31, 1960 / [Note on Box] / Second Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism / Sponsored by Hawaii Committee on Alcoholism / 1:30 p.m.: "Health, Education, Social Services" / Panel: / Walter B. Quisenberry, MD, Moderator / Mr. David A. Bowers / Mr. Patrick Bulter / Richard K. C. Lee, MD / Miss Mary L. Noonan / Mr. W. Tate Robinson / Dr. Willard Wilson / Discussion
      1:30 p.m.: "The Clergyman" -Seminar / Introduction - Mr. John C. Martelon / Panel: / The Reverend John J. Morrett, Moderator / The Reverend William R. Grosh / The Reverend Lawrence S. Jones / Mr. John C. Martelon / Discussion"
    - [Reel III] The Physician; The Nurse, 03/31/1960; mann_m_036; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Recording of 2nd Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism in Honolulu, Hawaii on March 30 and 31, 1960 / [Note on Box] / Second Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism / Sponsored by Hawaii Committee on Alcoholism / 1:30 p.m.: "The Physician" / Introduction - Alvin V. Majoska, MD / Panel: / Aloysius S. Church, MD, Moderator / James G. Harrison, MD / Alvin V. Majoska, MD / Major Lawrence C. McGonagle USA (MC) / Captain John F. McMullin USA (MC) / Thomas S. Min, MD / Discussion
      1:30 p.m.: "The Nurse" / Introduction - Walter B. Quisenberry, MD / Panel: / Sister Maureen (Keleher) O.S.F., Moderator / Mrs. Wilma Amalu, RN / Mrs. Rosie K. Chang, RN / Aloysius S. Church, MD / Discussion"
    - [Reel IV] [The Law], 03/30/1960; mann_m_037; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
      "Second Transpacific Conference on Alcoholism / Sponsored by Hawaii Committee on Alcoholism
      Track I / 1:30 p.m. The Law / Panel: / Mr. Patrick Butler, Moderator / Warden Joe C. Harper / Chief Daniel S.C. Liu / Mr. John C. Martelon / Mr. John H. Peters / Judge Harry Steiner
      Discussion
      March 30, 1960
      Sheraton Meeting House / Princess Kaiulani Hotel / Honolulu, Hawaii"
  - Treatment and Rehabilitation of Patients with Alcoholism, University of Utah College of Medicine, Salt Lake City,Utah, June 21-23, 1967
    - [1 of 4], mann_m_064; (1) Introductions; (2) "Early Detection and Prevention" - Marvin Block, M.D.; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    - [2 of 4], mann_m_065; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      (2) "Early Detection and Prevention" - Marvin Block, M.D. (cont); (3) "Long-Term Management of Alcoholism" - Vernelle Fox, M.D., C. Craig Nelson, M.D.; (4) "New Trends in Alcoholism" - Mrs. Marty Mann; (5) "Etiology of Alcoholism" - James A. Knight, M.D.
    - [3 of 4], mann_m_066; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      (6) Panel, "Drug Use and Abuse" - Faculty of School of Alcohol Studies, University of Utah; (7) "Neurological Complications of Alcoholism" - Huntington Mavor, M.D.; (8) Panel, "Treatment of Alcoholism in Clinics" - Gordon R. Evans, M.D., Vernelle Fox, M.D., C. Craig Nelson, M.D.
    - [4 of 4], mann_m_067; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      (8 cont.) Panel, "Treatment of Alcoholism in Clinics" - Gordon R. Evans, M.D., Vernelle Fox, M.D., C. Craig Nelson, M.D.
  - TV Program "At Random," Social Drinker, ...Alcoholic...," Chicago, Illinois, 05/26/1963; mann_m_050; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From back of box] "At Random" / 12:05 to 3:00 A.M. May 26, 1963 / Chicago, Ill / Social Drinker / ...Alcoholic... / Carter Davidson's Guests / Dr. Marvin Block, Psychiatrist Chairman of the Committee on Alcoholism Council on Mental Health, A.M.A. / Dr. Arthur H. Cain, Psychologist, Author, Consultant to the National Council on ALcoholism / Dr. Richard Cook, Psychiatrist / Mrs. Evelyn Echols, Vice President of Mental Health Society of greater Chicago / Samuel Peskin, Acting Director of the Chicago Committee on Alcoholism / Joseph Thurston, Consultant to the Board of Health with A.A. / Louis Abatta former Inmate of Prison, Now working with Inmates of Terra Haute Ind. Penitentiary / recorded on both sides on 2 track - 3 3/4 I.P.S
    [From inside box] Side 1 / General group discussion. Side one covers in part: Definition, symptoms, importance of early detection. Importance to industry. Private and group therapy. Motivation of individual. Good delineation of types of alcoholism. AA Fellowship Club of Police Department. Difference between AA groups, tendency to over-stress.
    Side II Prison AA groups described. Psychological vs physical addiction. More precise definition given. Prolonged wrangle about AA and word meanings. Entire second side is far below first."
  - Two Way Street, Elmira, New York, 01/03/1963; mann_m_051; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From front of box] a 90 min. radio program produced by WELM, Elmira, New York, with cooperation of Elmira Information Center
    [From back of box] Alcoholism - A two way street produced by WELM in cooperation with the Chemung County Council on Alcoholism / 90 min.
    [From inside box] "Two Way Street" / a one hour radio program produced by W.E.L.M., Elmira, N.Y. and Chemung County Alcoholism Information Center. Program is Built around image of alcoholism as a steep two-way street which people travel in both directions: Sam a professional man; George, a factory worker; Mary, a housewife; and Jane, the wife of an alcoholic, tell their stories. The Roman Catholic Chaplain of Elmira prison talks on crime and alcoholism. a simulated interview at the Alcoholism Information Center is Presented. Finally the story returns to Sam, George, Mary and Jane as they tell of the rewards they found on the way up the road. / This device, the two-way street, is good but the program is much too long and too slow of pace. The voices, while undoubtedly authentic, are unclear, often tiresome, and the overall effect of this program is deadly after the first 15 minutes or so."
  - [U.S. Army Alcohol Abuse Conference] Selected Speaker Highlights, 06/13/1972; mann_m_081; reel tape (Box 15)
    [From box]: First U.S. Army Alcohol Abuse Conf. Ft. George G. Meade, MD / Speakers: / C.E. Hutchins / Sen. Harold E. Hughes / Marty Mann
  - What the Alcoholic Owes to Marty Mann, New York, NY, Jan 1963; mann_m_095; 10" phonodisc
    Interview with Marty Mann by Barbara Wright for Reader's Digest
  - WSDE-TV Editorial, Alcohol Information Week, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1960; mann_m_044; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From note inside box] A.I.W TV Editorial 3 Minutes / Excellent description of opening of Information Center and what it is prepared to do for the community
  - Yvelin Gardner, American Lutheran TV Program, New York, NY, 12/07/1962; mann_m_053; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
  - [Yvelin] Gardner, "A Decade of Progress" and "Talk to AA Doctors," Clayton, New York, 06/18/1958; mann_m_058; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
    [From note on interior] Mr. Gardner Talk / "A Decade of Progress" / Changing ideas at first, only an alcoholic could do anything for others. Now know any trained person can, and several disciplines needed. Ten years have seen "disease education" change to "health education." Development of public understanding and the role of doctors, medicine, psychiatry, clinics, hospitals and the AMA, state, church, and law all outlined. Importance of "total push" to combine effectively is stressed."
  - Yvelin Gardner interview on "The Jo Halperin Show," WOR Radio New York 710 AM, mann_m_096; 10" phonodisc
  - Yvelin Gardner on the John Windgate Show, New York, NY, 03/28/2013; mann_m_092; phonodisc
  - Yvelin Gardner on "The Open Mind" pt 1, White Plains, New York, 03/10/1957; mann_m_091a; 12" phonodisc
  - Yvelin Gardner on "The Open Mind" pt 2, White Plains, New York, 03/10/1957; mann_m_091b; 12" phonodisc
  - Yvelin Gardner, "Where do we stand today on alcoholism?" Massey University, New Zealand, 01/25/1966; mann_m_040; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
  - [unidentified organization] 6th annual meeting, New York, NY, Part I of II: Morning session, 03/12/1952; mann_m_005; talks by The Reverend Otis Rice and Dr. Selden D. Bacon; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
  - [unidentified organization] 6th annual meeting, New York, NY, Part II of II: Luncheon session, 03/12/1952; mann_m_006; Fulton Oursler; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
    [From Back]: This recordings has one SIDE ONE the talk by Mr. Fulton Oursler, Author and Senior Editor of ALCOHOLISM, introducted by Mrs. Marty Mann; AND the talk by Mrs. Marty Mann, Executive Director of the National Committee on Alcoholism and author of Primer on Alcoholism, WHERE WE STAND TODAY. / SIDE TWO: ALCOHOLISM AND LEGISLATION by COl. Harold W. Riegelman, Chairman New York State Coordinating Committee on Alcoholism; and ALCOHOLISM AND MEDICINE by Dr. Harold W. Lovell, author, Hope and Help for the Alcoholic. (Sixth Annual Meeting National Committee on Alcoholism, New Yor [sic], March 12th, 1952. recordings by Cape Town Two, Sparks Maryland, U.S.A. Details on talk written on note inside.
  - [unidentified organization] Annual Meeting, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1965; mann_m_018; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 9)
    [From front of box] "The New Orleans Story" - Mr. Ashton Brisolara, Executive Director, Committee on Alcoholism for Greater New Orleans / "A service of Value" - Marty Mann
    [From back of box] Take #8 / [illegible], Pampleian / 4:05 - P.M. / Fri public session closing speakers / (M.M 202) / Side 1 Ashton Brisolara / / 514 "
  - [unidentified organization] Annual Meeting, Homeless & Institutional Alcoholics, 1959
    - Reel I, 1959; mann_m_071; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      Side 1 Capt. George Duplain. Salvation Army program for rehabilitation / talk breaks off in mid-flight
      Side 2 Robert S. Aikenhead. Possible rehabilitation of the Skid-Row Alcoholic."
    - Reel II, 03/19/1959; mann_m_072; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      Side I / Walter C. Hart "Volunteers of America" (Tape breaks off at early part and never continues)
      Side II / W.L. Hindman absent. (His paper read by William Plunkert "Skid Row and Urban Renewal"
    - Reel III, 1959; mann_m_073; 1/4" reel tape (Oversize 10)
      [From note inside box] Dr. Warren Durham / "The Migrant Worker and Rehabilitation of Vagrants." / (Talk breaks off toward end)"
    - [Reel IV?], 03/22/1960; mann_m_074; 1/4" reel tape (Box 15)
      "panel discussion on homeless and institutional alcoholics / track 1 / talk by Myerson / track 2 / talk by Mackelman"
  - [no label], mann_m_177; cassette (Box 15)